<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Scott&#39;s Test Blog</title>
        <link>http://scott.maclure.info/tech/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Scott&#39;s Test Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 16:24:31 +0800</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://scott.maclure.info/tech/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>Hello, World!</title>
            <link>http://scott.maclure.info/tech/posts/2020/hello-world/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 16:24:31 +0800</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://scott.maclure.info/tech/posts/2020/hello-world/</guid>
            <description>Welcome Hello? Is this thing on? Good. Welcome to my tech blog. Here you will find all sorts of stuff that I&amp;rsquo;ve found interesting while working as a consultant and developer for cloud infrastructure and automation, with an eye for security &amp;amp; compliance concerns at scale.
I also blog about stuff that I find interesting, strictly within the tech space. So that includes side-projects and whatnot.
Disclaimer: All content here are my opinions alone, and do not formally represent those of my employers - past, present, or future.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="welcome">Welcome</h2>
<p>Hello? Is this thing on? Good. Welcome to my tech blog. Here you will find all sorts of stuff that I&rsquo;ve found interesting while working as a consultant and developer for cloud infrastructure and automation, with an eye for security &amp; compliance concerns at scale.</p>
<p>I also blog about stuff that I find interesting, strictly within the tech space. So that includes side-projects and whatnot.</p>
<p><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> All content here are my opinions alone, and do not formally represent those of my employers - past, present, or future.</p>
<h2 id="who-am-i">Who Am I?</h2>
<p>Follow the links to find out more:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://scott.maclure.info/cv/">https://scott.maclure.info/cv/</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/scott-maclure/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/scott-maclure/</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/ScottMaclure/">https://github.com/ScottMaclure/</a></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="how-did-i-set-this-blog-up">How did I set this blog up?</h2>
<p>Let&rsquo;s start with some desired outcomes:</p>
<ul>
<li>Keep it simple - strip back the end-end worklow to minimise moving parts.</li>
<li>It&rsquo;s gotta be &ldquo;almost-free&rdquo; to host&hellip;</li>
<li>AND there won&rsquo;t be any spikes in cost (beware free tiers in Cloud providers!)</li>
<li>Its easy to author</li>
<li>I can setup a minimalistic css theme without much effort</li>
<li>It has tagging support</li>
<li>I don&rsquo;t care about authoring from mobile - desktop|laptop will be fine.</li>
</ul>
<p>My solution:</p>
<ul>
<li>The maclure.info domain I had already registered via Amazon&rsquo;s Route 53 service. So I&rsquo;ll use R53 to manage DNS.</li>
<li>The code for most of my projects are hosted on github, which has support for &ldquo;<a href="https://pages.github.com/">pages</a>&rdquo;, which is (free) static hosting, AND custom domain names are supported. Perfect.</li>
<li><a href="https://gohugo.io/">Hugo</a> is a static site generator I&rsquo;ve used in the past, seems decent and fast, with some nice themes. That means I can locally compile, removing the need for an external build server.</li>
</ul>
<p>The end result is that I can do the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>I can run a local server and preview my drafts</li>
<li>I can commit and push drafts up to github without changing the deployed site content</li>
<li>I can configure Hugo to build the static site into /docs subfolder, which is compatible with github&rsquo;s hosting</li>
<li>I can &ldquo;publish&rdquo; content by setting &ldquo;draft: false&rdquo; in the metadata, running the &ldquo;hugo&rdquo; binary, then git commit &amp; git push</li>
<li>I maintain zero-infrastructure! Well, I manage a domain, that&rsquo;s it.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="whats-next">What&rsquo;s next?</h2>
<p>Over time I will write and publish blog posts focused around whatever I&rsquo;m learning or playing with at the time.</p>
<p>This will mostly be for my learning benefit, as I find being able to write about a topic in a manner that explains it to someone else <em>really</em> helps me to internalise my own understanding of the content.</p>
<p>So yeah, this blog is mainly for me, but written for public consumption also.</p>
<p>Welcome.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
